Guide to the Gay Cable Network Archives, 1982-2001 MSS.231
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series XXII: Pride and Progress / The Right Stuff, 1985-1990; 154235
  - 1987, 246559
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 6 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 2/2/1987], February 1987; ID: 231.0724; 156319 (Box 46, Media ID: 231.0724)
      11. Paper finds that certain DNA viruses have the ability to activate latent AIDS viruses
      12. Senator Edward Kennedy promises adequate AIDS budget beyond Reagan's lackluster budget
      14. New segment Lavender Health, presented by the Office of Gay and Lesbian Health Concerns of the New York City Department of Health, discussion of AIDS-phobia
      15. George Trahanis interviews Jeff Goodman, Secretary of the Board of the Greater Gotham Business Council
      2. GCN Cincinnati TV episode, "Georgia Vice"
      3. Show Bits with George Trahanis, review of Broadway musical "Beehive"
      4. COMMERCIAL: Night of a Thousand Gowns charity ball
      5. Olivia Negron interviews Gerard Ilaria, a volunteer social worker at New York Hospital and Columbia University Gay Health Advocacy Project
      6. Razor Sharp introduces a contest to win a date with her
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 7 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 2/10/1987], February 1987; ID: 231.0725; 156320 (Box 46, Media ID: 231.0725)
      1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Darrell Yates Rist, Joyce Hunter, and Jim Levin
      3. Updates about the March on Washington, including discussion of the demands of community on government
      COMMERCIAL: Night of a Thousand Gowns charity drag ball
      3. Criticism of GMHC's lack of an active political front, and emphasis on social service in the community
      4. Gay rights advocate and psychiatrist, Emery Hetrick's obituary
      5. News Watch, a study by the University of California, Berkeley finds that gay men who only engage in oral sex or insertive anal intercourse have a lower risk of contracting AIDS virus
      6. Philadelphia, a gay city employee charges the city with violation of its gay rights law by not allowing his lover certain rights
      7. San Francisco, openly gay Tom Nolan elected President of the San Mateo Board of Supervisors
      8. People traveling to Mexico to buy experimental AIDS treatment drugs will be prosecuted to the fullest extent of the law as drug smugglers
      9. Warren, Michigan, mayor bans local cable company from airing gay program "The Lambda Report" on its public access channel
      10. San Francisco, two former members of the satirical protest group, The Sisters of Perpetual Indulgence, register legally as the "official San Francisco 1987 papal welcoming committee"
      12. Lavender Health, interview with Stephen Schaefer, coordinator of the AIDS Hotline
      13. George Trahanis's closing statement
      2. Show Bits with George Trahanis, review of "Blue is for Boys" and interview with actor, Allen Gassman
      3. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, short news stories
      4. Judell interviews Canadian comedian, Lorne Elliott
      5. Razor Sharp introduces a contest to win a date with her
      6. Olivia Negron, closing statements
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 8 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 2/17/1987], February 1987; ID: 231.0726; 156321 (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0726)
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 9 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 2/23/1987] [3]--Men and Films, Episode No. 9, February 1987; ID: 231.0727; 156322 (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0727)
      1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Darrell Yates Rist, and Tim Coglin
      3. New York Native reports that AIDS caused by syphilis spirochetes
      4. Catholic Church ejecting gay groups from their churches and forbidding them to meet or worship there
      5. Andy Humm on the marriage of an ex-gay man with AIDS in a Catholic Church
      6. News Watch, bill introduced in Maryland to remove state's sodomy laws
      7. LAMBDA legal defense hires a third attorney to full-time staff to deal exclusively with AIDS-related issues
      8. Chicago, low income gays suffer discrimination at a greater rate and degree
      9. New York, judge rules that funeral homes charging more for burial of AIDS victims are doing so illegally
      10. San Francisco, Mayor Diane Feinstein announces a reward for information leading to the arrest of the murderer of two gay men in the city's Castro district in December of 1986
      11. Arizona governor, Evan Mecham, declares that homosexuality is not a valid alternative lifestyle and therefore has no place in any argument concerning human rights
      13. Lavender Health, interview with Dr. Joan Waitkevicz of the lesbian-centered St. Marks Women's Health Collective
      1. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, interview with William H. Hoffman, playwright of "As Is," with clips of the television film
      2. Show Bits with George Trahanis, review of "Vicki's Valentine Thing," with clips
      3. Razor Sharp introduces a contest to win a date with her
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 10 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 3/2/1987], March 1987; ID: 231.0728; 156323 (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0728)
      1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Eleanor Cooper, and Christopher [Wolfe]
      3. Discussion of condom distribution and the public airing of condom ads on network television, getting the gay community "condom comfortable"
      COMMERCIAL: Jose Sarria for SF AIDS Foundation
      4. Mandatory testing for HIV for those working in the public sector
      5. Andy Humm demonstrates proper condom use
      6. News Watch, Chicago Resource Center awards National Coalition of Black Lesbians and Gays $10,000 to support their magazine, "Black Out"
      7. California Fair Employment and Housing Commission unanimously rules persons with AIDS protected against discrimination on the job
      8. New Hepatitis B vaccine not derived from human blood products now in mass production and widely available
      9. BBC cancels plans to air a two part educational drama on homosexuality due to heated public debate on sex education in schools
      11. Lavender Health, interview with Richard Burns, executive director of the Lesbian and Gay Communi
      2. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, announcement of Robert Latourneau's death, clips from "Boys in the Band"
      3. The late Arthur Bell's interview of Robert Latourneau from the "Emerald City Tapes"
      4. Show Bits, George Trahanis reviews the off-Broadway production, "The Musical Comedy Murders of 1940"
      COMMERCIAL: Judge Steven Lachs for the NGTF Fund for Human Dignity
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 11 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 3/6/1987], March 1987; ID: 231.0729; 156324 (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0729)
      1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Darrell Yates Rist, and Jim Levin, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
      3. Discussion of the Center for Disease Control Conference in Atlanta, and the growing nuance in AIDS discussion
      4. Discussion of the radical Lavender Hill Mob movement and its public disturbance as a protest method
      5. Andy Humm on the conflict between organized religion and homosexuality
      6. News Watch, Delaware State Insurance Commission approves gay-sensitive health insurance guidelines
      7. Chicago, "gay dollar" stamps now sold by mail
      8. National Gay Rights Advocates publish a tax guide for gay and lesbian men and women
      9. California's State Association of Health calls for the isolated quarantining of those who are AIDS and HIV positive and are willfully spreading the virus
      10. Sports Report, interview with two members of the Big Apple Softball League
      11. Lavender Health, interview with John Thacker, director of the NYC Department of Health's Sexually Transmitted Disease Education Service
      2. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, interview with actor Taylor Mead, clips from Andy Warhol's "Frankenstein"
      3. Show Bits with George Trahanis, review of "Mona Rogers in Person," with clips
      4. Interview series on the operating methods of GMHC, with playwright Larry Kramer, and a response by the executive director of GMHC, Richard Dunne
      5. Closing credits over the end of Dunne's response which is cut off
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 12 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 3/13/1987], March 1987; ID: 231.0730; 156325 (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0730)
      1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Darrell Yates Rist, Joyce Hunter, and Jim Levin, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
      3. Discussion of Catholic Archdiocese's banning of Catholic gay rights groups from churches
      4. One year anniversary of the passing of New York City's gay right bill, with clips from GCN's coverage of the event, and discussion of the progress of gay rights since the bill
      5. Andy Humm on the growing participation of the gay community in activism
      6. News Watch, Vatican newspaper criticizes condom use as a method of stopping spread of AIDS, advocating the stopping of gay sex
      7. Seattle Times rejects an ad from Parents and Friends of Lesbians and Gays, due to the use of the word "gay"
      8. Vermont, gay rights bill introduced in state legislature
      9. Delta Airlines avoids national gay boycott after Delta agrees to meet demands of gay group, including non-discrimination of passengers with AIDS
      10. Sports Report, with clips from the Dr. Ruth show
      11. Lavender Health, interview with Felicia Schady, public health educator with the Hepatitis B Prevention Unit at the NYC Health Department
      s
      2. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, interview with Helen [Schumaker], actress in the one-woman show, "Mona Rogers in Person," with clips
      3. Show Bits with George Trahanis, review of Barbara Gelb's two-act, one-character play "My Gene"
      4. Second part of the interview series on the operating methods of GMHC, with playwright Larry Kramer, and a response by the executive director of GMHC, Richard Dunne, tape cuts off
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 13 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 3/20/1987], March 1987; ID: 231.0731; 156326 (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0731)
      3. Discussion of the increasing activism within the gay community, ties to "civil disobedience," and how to encourage new faces to join the protest
      4. New York Times reports that Southern voters are extremely concerned with AIDS as a priority issue, discussion of how the AIDS issue will be used by politicians in the 1988 election
      5. Andy Humm on the AIDS education of teenagers
      6. News Watch, new study shows that the longer a person is infected with HIV, the greater their chance is of developing AIDS
      7. Madison Avenue advertising firm denounce remark by Lifestyles Condoms, who stated "AIDS is a condom-marketers dream"
      8. AZT renamed to Retrovir, to limit confusion in foreign countries where AZT is the name of an immuno-suppressant
      9. Sacramento Union publishes profile of gay male couple for Valentine series, and receives complaints
      11. Lavender Health, interview with Liz [Walker], head of Domestic Violence Services at NYC Gay and Lesbian Anti-Violence Project
      2. Show Bits with George Trahanis, review of Barbara Lea's cabaret show, "The Melody Lingers On"
      3. Naming Names segment, exposing persons in the media who misrepresent gay and lesbian people, sponsored by GLAAD: John Cardinal O'Connor
      COMMERCIAL: "Suds" gay soap opera, created by GCN
      4. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, interview with Stephen McCauley, author of "Object of My Affection"
      5. Third part of the interview series on the operating methods of GMHC, with playwright Larry Kramer, and a response by the executive director of GMHC, Richard Dunne, tape cuts off
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 14 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 3/27/1987], March 1987; ID: 231.0732; 156327 (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0732)
      1. Coverage by Andy Humm of the AIDS crisis demonstration at Trinity Church on March 24, 1987, interview with Larry Kramer
      2. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Darrell Yates Rist, and Jim Levin, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
      3. Short news stories, appeal for donations
      3. Discussion of the New York Times coverage of AIDS issue, quality of series and whether it was timely or too-little-too-late
      4. Continued discussion of New York Times AIDS coverage
      5. Andy Humm on New York City's AIDS education
      6. News Watch, Senator Pete Wilson introduces a bill to create a Congressional Advisory Panel on AIDS, headed by the National Academy of Sciences
      7. Senator Dan Burton of Indiana proposes a bill for mandatory annual HIV testing for all US residents
      8. New York, Queens co-op agrees to let a gay couple purchase an apartment after the couple went to the city's Commission on Human Rights
      9. Congressional Hearing on AIDS Education finds that Federal response to AIDS epidemic is "slow, limited, and ultimately impotent"
      11. Lavender Health, interview with Dava Weinstein, social worker, and co-chair of "10% of Those We Serve" chemical dependency conference
      12. George Trahanis announces GCN's 5th anniversary, and a new pledge drive
      1. Episode of GCN's soap opera, "Suds": "A Farewell to Tom"
      2. Closing credits
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 15 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 4/7/1987], April 1987; ID: 231.0733; 156328 (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0733)
      1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Darrell Yates Rist, Kitty Cotter, and Jim Levin, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
      2. Discussion of the 1987 National Lesbian and Gay Health Conference, and AIDS in politics overtaking gay rights issues
      3. Discussion of the AIDS and HIV tests, and personal issues surrounding testing
      4. Andy Humm on "straightening up" a home to hide a homosexual lifestyle
      5. News Watch, Georgia State Representative shelves legislation to criminalize homosexual sodomy due to controversy created
      6. "Names Project," a quilt of the names of those killed by AIDS to be displayed on Washington Mall during the March on Washington
      7. Philadelphia school-board condemns harassment of students based on sexual orientation, provides "sensitivity training" for teachers and administrators
      8. Independent Catholic newspaper estimates that 50% of Catholic priests in the US are homosexual
      10. Lavender Health, interview with Mary Anne Chaisson, member of the Department of Health's AIDS research unit, which collects data and tracks the epidemic in NYC
      1. Naming Names, Lifestyles and Trojan Condoms criticized for calling AIDS "a condom-makers dream" and refusing to advertise in gay publications
      COMMERCIAL: 10th Annual Awards Evening for the Fund for Human Dignity
      2. Media Watch, with Brandon Judell, interview with John Dietrich of the Islanders Club, an adventure-oriented club
      COMMERCIAL: GCN Fundraiser
      3. Episode of GCN's soap opera, "Suds": "See Spot Run"
      5. COMMERCIAL: GCN Fundraiser
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 16 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 4/15/1987], April 1987; ID: 231.0734; 156329 (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0734)
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 17 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 4/20/1987], April 1987; ID: 231.0735; 156330 (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0735)
      2. Announcement of GCN Pledge Month
      3. Discussion of openly-gay Harry Britt's loss to Nancy Pelosi for the position of Californian Democratic member of Congress, discussion of gay politicians and the gay voting block
      4. Vice-President George Bush finally takes a stance on AIDS prevention and education, but only in the private sphere, also the outspokenness of Surgeon General Everett Koop
      5. AIDS organizations in Puerto Rico
      6. Anti-gay prejudice and heterosexual bias
      7. News Watch, Georgetown University persuades a Maryland state representative a bill to give them funding for an expansion, after the university refused to comply with Washington DC's human rights law
      8. Idaho requires those applying for a marriage license to be tested for HIV
      9. Moscow, USSR opens an anonymous AIDS testing site for foreigners and those who have had sex with foreigners
      10. Britain's Princess Diana opens the country's first AIDS ward, in order to dispel myth of infection by close contact
      11. Sports Report, on location with The Times Squares, a gay-oriented square dance group
      12. Lavender Health, interview with Karen Solomon, a coordinator of the AIDS Counseling and Testing Site of the NYC Department of Health, discussion of HIV test
      1. Show Bits with George Trahanis, review of Broadway production of Harvey Fierstein's three one-acts, "Safe Sex"
      2. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, interview with [Frederick] Davies, star of the one-man show, "The Great Truman Capote"
      3. Episode of GCN's soap opera, "Suds": "Catching Up is Hard to Do"
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 18 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 4/27/1987], April 1987; ID: 231.0736; 156331 (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0736)
      1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Darrell Yates Rist, NYU student David Strah, and Jim Levin, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
      3. Discussion of Brooklyn College refusal to give award to anti-gay Catholic Bishop Francis J. Mugavero, the political backlash against Brooklyn College's decision, and how the gay community can confront religious bigotry
      4. Condom availability in prisons and in colleges, whether condoms are "catching on"
      5. Andy Humm on the necessity of activists and volunteers in the gay community
      6. News Watch, anti-gay psychologist Paul Cameron changes the name of his organization to "The Family Research Institute"
      7. Oklahoma, Republican Party platform is anti-gay, despite the Republican governor's approval of sex education in schools
      8. Hollywood, television shows and films win awards at the Alliance for Gay and Lesbian Artists awards for positive portrayals of gay characters
      9. Dallas police arm selves with gloves, masks, and insect repellent due to fear of contracting AIDS
      10. Clips from a speech by New York Governor Mario Cuomo, on the passage of an executive order for the protection of gay and lesbian employees
      COMMERCIAL: Dancing Cheek to Cheek GCN event
      11. Lavender Health, interview with Damien Martin, co-founder of the Institute for the Protection of Lesbian and Gay Youth and Professor at New York University, about specific needs in educating gay youths
      1. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, short stories and clip of Mayor Koch talking about Ronald Reagan's inactivity regarding AIDS funding
      2. Naming Names, criticism of Max Frankel of the New York Times
      3. Episode 5 of GCN's soap opera, "Suds": "A Brief Crisis"
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 19 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 5/4/1987], May 1987; ID: 231.0737; 156332 (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0737)
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 20 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 5/11/1987], May 1987; ID: 231.0738; 156333 (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0738)
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 21 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 5/15/1987], May 1987; ID: 231.0739; 156334 (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0739)
      1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, David Strah, Phil Reed, and Jim Levin, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
      2. "Condom Consciousness Day" at NYU, distribution of condoms
      3. President Reagan and his non-stance on AIDS testing, and public policy
      4. Discussion of politicians in-the-running for the Democratic nomination and their pro or anti-gay stance
      5. News Watch, AIDS drug, DDC, enters preliminary human testing
      6. Record book of 500 people tested for the HIV virus has been stolen, presumably by blackmailers
      7. Alliance for Gay and Lesbian Artists closes its offices and lays off its staff
      8. Coverage and clips from NYC's "Stamp Out AIDS Day"
      10. Lavender Health, interview with Donna Futterman, pediatrician and co-author of a lesbian parenting book
      1. Show Bits with George Trahanis, review of "Waving Goodbye"
      2. Naming Names, criticism of Jerry Falwell
      3. South Padre Island, Texas, gay resort location Lyle's Deck
      4. Episode 8 of GCN's soap opera, "Suds": "Fit for a Queen"
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 22 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 5/26/1987], May 1987; ID: 231.0740; 156335 (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0740)
      1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, David Strah, Joyce Hunter, and Christopher Lynn, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
      2. Discussion of the lawsuit against Governor Cuomo's "anti-sex guidelines"
      3. Discussion of gay activism against anti-gay politicians and finding allies in politics
      4. Balancing sex education and AIDS education for children and young adults
      5. Andy Humm on politicians advocating abstinence to counter AIDS
      6. News Watch, CDC adds dementia and emaciation to AIDS symptoms
      7. Holland, upscale condom boutique opens on outskirts of Amsterdam's red light district
      8. Smoking found to possibly cause impotence
      9. A Florida man goes on a shooting rampage because he believed that some people thought he was gay
      11. Lavender Health, Ron Vauchon with Ellen Zaltzberg discussing various conferences centered around gay health issues
      1. Show Bits with George Trahanis, interview with Bob Bowyer of the off-Broadway show, "Funny Feet"
      2. Olivia Negron interviews Karen Abbott and Bob Werner, two activists who placed pro-gay stickers around "Heritage USA," the park owned by Tammy Faye and Jim Bakker
      3. Interview with Joe di Sabito about condom companies avoiding advertising in gay media
      4. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, interview with Mark Thompson, author and cultural editor of "The Advocate" magazine
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 23 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 5/29/1987], May 1987; ID: 231.0741; 156336 (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0741)
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 24 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 6/5/1987], June 1987; ID: 231.0742; 156394 (Box 48, Media ID: 231.0742)
      1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, David Strah, Joyce Hunter, and Jim Levin, sponsored by the Human Rights Campaign Fund
      2. Updates regarding the National March on Washington for Lesbian and Gay Rights
      3. Discussion of a new biography of Leonard Bernstein that outs him and multiple others in his circle, and the status of closeted celebrities
      4. Ronald Reagan and George Bush booed after speaking in favor of mandatory AIDS testing, also necessity of having medical professionals discuss the issues, and not politicians
      5. Andy Humm on Mario Cuomo and Ed Koch "getting tough" on AIDS and the issue of mandatory testing
      6. Clips from President Reagan and Vice-President George Bush's speeches on mandatory testing, booing of audience, and clips from the June 1st 1987 protest in front of the White House
      7. News Watch, French researchers discover second, genetically different strain of HIV which also causes AIDS
      8. "The San Francisco Chronicle" apologizes for omitting the names of surviving homosexual partners in obituaries
      9. In a national poll, AIDS is found to be the third greatest fear of youths aged 8-17, behind only kidnapping and nuclear war, with 65% saying they are "very concerned" with AIDS, and other statistics
      10. Liberace's estate sues Riverside County, CA as the coroner's linking the star's death with AIDS damaged his posthumous reputation
      COMMERCIAL: Lesbian and Gay Community Services Center